# Aleimar P. Villabrille

Taguig City, Philippines | 09984860798

apvillabrille@pm.me | aleimar.github.io/apvillabrille17

Young and motivated developer, passionate in bringing ideas to life. Proficient in research, full-stack development, and project management. Believes that people and technology can make the world a better place than it was yesterday.

### **CORE COMPETENCIES**

- Research and Analytics
- Programming
- Project Management

- Corporate Communication
- Creative innovation
- Problem-solving

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Digital Specialist and Developer**, EastWest Banking Corporation (September 2019–Present)

Developed and improved business process using AI and automation of different operations and products from acquisition to delivery of credit cards, personal loan and auto loans.

- Initiates demo and presentation to executive-level heads from different departments to propose solutions and prototype in order to optimize processes using technologies.
- Developed acquisition chatbot using Node JS for credit cards, personal loan, and auto loan.
- Responsible for database management and cost analysis of Digital Channels resources.
- Ability manage time for development and delivery of multiple projects.
- Research with latest technology to improve current bank processes under consumer lending cluster

**Bioinformatics Intern**, Philippine Genome Center (June 2019 – July 2019)

Six weeks training and internship by Philippine Genome Center and Department of Science and Technology.

- Research project focused on Molecular Dynamics Simulation and Modelling of integrins.
  Supervised and worked under the project of Protein Structure and Immunology Laboratory of the National Institute of Molecular Biology and Biotechnology.
- Research presented for poster presentation at the 2019 International Union of Biochemistry and Molecular Biology, and Philippine Society for Biochemistry and Molecular Biology.

**Software Tester**, Detail Merchandising Online (May 2018 – July 2018)

Practicum as part of BS Computer Science Requirements. Worked under tester department.

- Learned web scraping concept and tools, and hands-on experience on Agile Project Management.
- Delivered excellent performance throughout our internship program.

## **EDUCATION AND CERTIFICATIONS**

BS Computer Science - University of the Philippines Mindanao, 2015 – 2019

• Honorific Awardee and Class 2019 Best Special Problem for Computer Science

Google Project Management Certificate, Ongoing

Business Analytics Specialization – Wharton University thru Coursera

#### REFERENCES

Doji Bringas – Assistant Vice President, EastWest Banking Corporation

• cebringas@eastwestbanker.com

Dominic 'Dom' Albao - Philippine Genome Center

• dsalbao@up.edu.ph